<story-context id=".bmad/bmm/workflows/4-implementation/story-context/template" v="1.0">
  <metadata>
    <epicId>3</epicId>
    <storyId>3.3</storyId>
    <title>Enforce one booking per user/day</title>
    <status>drafted</status>
    <generatedAt>2025-12-03</generatedAt>
    <generator>BMAD Story Context Workflow</generator>
    <sourceStoryPath>docs/sprint-artifacts/3-3-enforce-one-booking-per-user-day.md</sourceStoryPath>
  </metadata>

  <story>
    <asA>system</asA>
    <iWant>to block users from holding multiple desks on the same day</iWant>
    <soThat>conflicts are prevented</soThat>
    <tasks>
      <![CDATA[
      - Client pre-check: detect existing booking for user/date; block confirm with message (AC1, AC2)
      - Storage enforcement: reject writes with user/date conflict; return structured error (AC1, AC2)
      - Visitor handling: ensure visitor-uuid gets conflict checks (AC3)
      - Error UX: toast/inline message; leave UI state unchanged; rollback optimistic if used (AC1–AC3)
      - Tests: client conflict, storage conflict, visitor conflict, error handling
      ]]>
    </tasks>
  </story>

  <acceptanceCriteria>
    <![CDATA[
    1) Booking create blocked if user already has booking on date; clear message; no write. (docs/epics.md)
    2) Conflict validation runs client-side and storage-side to prevent races. (docs/epics.md)
    3) Visitor bookings treated as unique ids and also prevented from double-booking. (docs/epics.md)
    ]]>
  </acceptanceCriteria>

  <artifacts>
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      - path: docs/epics.md; title: Epics; section: Epic 3 Story 3.3; snippet: conflict rule and checks.
      - path: docs/prd.md; title: PRD; section: FR8; snippet: one booking per user/day requirement.
      - path: docs/architecture.md; title: Architecture; section: Storage validation; snippet: validation responsibility, deskId alignment.
      ]]>
    </docs>
    <code>
      <![CDATA[
      - None yet; implement conflict checks in storage and booking flow.
      ]]>
    </code>
    <dependencies>
      <![CDATA[
      - React 19.2.x
      - Vite 6.2.x
      - Radix UI 1.2.x (toast)
      ]]>
    </dependencies>
  </artifacts>

  <constraints>
    <![CDATA[
    - Enforce conflicts at storage as source of truth; UI pre-check for UX only.
    - Use userId + date key; include visitor-uuid.
    - No partial writes; rollback optimistic updates on failure.
    ]]>
  </constraints>

  <interfaces>
    <![CDATA[
    - checkConflict(userId, date): Promise<boolean>
    - createBooking(payload): Promise<Result<Booking>> // returns error code CONFLICT if blocked
    ]]>
  </interfaces>

  <tests>
    <standards><![CDATA[Vitest unit/API; React Testing Library for modal; consider Playwright conflict E2E.]]></standards>
    <locations><![CDATA[tests/unit/booking-conflict.test.ts, tests/component/BookingConfirm.conflict.spec.tsx]]></locations>
    <ideas><![CDATA[
    - AC1: Existing booking prevents new booking; error shown; no write.
    - AC2: Simulated race (two create calls) -> one succeeds, other gets CONFLICT.
    - AC3: Visitor booking conflict detected.
    ]]></ideas>
  </tests>
</story-context>
